Hi, I'm Ned Smith and I am a researcher in
trusted computing. I've spent 30 years
doing hardware trusted computing and I'm
also interested in secure asset transfers
based on protocols that are being defined
in the Internet Engineering Task Force.
And my presentation today was to overview
where we're at with the definition of the
SATP protocol. In particular, how a SATP
protocol is tied to authorization
mechanisms that are important for legal
responsibility when assets are
transferred. Yeah, so one of the things
that sets me apart as a researcher in
trusted computing is my experience working
with trust both from a hardware side but
also from an infrastructure side. And
focused a lot of my career around this
notion of device attestation which is
providing evidence about the environment
in which applications or workloads run so
that a remote entity can verify that the
environment is trustworthy not only that
the workload is trustworthy. And so I'm
incorporating that kind of thinking into
to not only the work that's being done in
the ITF in the RATS working group which I
chair but also in other standards and
architectures that I influence.